LAID-BACK CAMP SEASON 3
《搖曳露營△ (第三季)》
EPISODE 8: THE ONSLAUGHT OF MOUTH-WATERING FOOD!!
(第8話 要開始曬美食囉)
Hello, everyone. This is Aoi Inuyama.
大家好 我是犬山葵
We had a great time at the yakitori place
因為我們在烤雞肉串店吃得太開心
and missed the bus,
不小心錯過公車
so we changed our route and took the mountain road.
只好改變路線 走山路過去
Despite the many obstacles along the way,
雖然一路上遇到許多狀況
the Bus Campers made it
最終我們這群公車露營客
to Mount Mizugaki campsite.
還是順利抵達了瑞牆山露營場
What will become of the bags full of blemished tomatoes?
之前塞滿一整袋的瑕疵番茄 會變成什麼料理呢?
Will Nadeshiko be able to resist our mouth-watering food attack?
撫子又能否抵擋得住 我們的曬美食攻擊呢?
And is Hanpen really a dog that exists?
而半片到底是不是 真實存在的狗狗呢?
We shall find out in the second part of the half-reality,
讓我們接著看真假參半的 瑞牆露營回憶後半篇
BUS CAMP
(公車露營) (野活會剩下的成員的回憶露營)
If only I'd ordered it earlier!
早知道剛才就先吃了
This yakitori is amazing!
烤雞肉串超讚的
But there's one more thing.
除此之外 還有另一個東西
Come on, eat it while it's hot.
來 趁熱吃吧
It's nice, isn't it?
這樣也挺不錯的吧?
Can't we just have a nice, peaceful night by the campfire?
難得的露營之夜 就不能安靜地度過嗎
SATURDAY, 21 MARCH 20XX 4:12 PM MOUNT MIZUGAKI CAMP
(20XX年3月21日星期六) (下午4點12分 瑞牆山露營場)
I think it's the landmark?
該說是地標嗎
Campsites with such beautiful scenery are truly amazing.
像這種有風景的露營場 果然很棒呢
I get it.
我懂…
Places like mountains or the sea, even cityscapes are nice too.
比如山或海之類的 還有街景也不錯
Mount Mizugaki is famous for hiking,
瑞牆山雖然是以登山聞名
but it has many rock climbing spots too.
但好像也有很多攀岩景點喔
Near the summit, there's a prominent rock called
山頂附近有一塊突出的岩石
"Oyasuri Rock."
叫"大銼刀岩"
Greetings!
嗨
People actually climb that rock face.
就是要攀爬那面岩壁喔
Climbing such a dangerous place, wow!
居然要爬那麼危險的地方啊
I'm good just admiring it from afar.
我還是在下面遠遠眺望它就好了
Same.
我也這麼覺得
But the view from up there
但是
must be spectacular.
從上面俯瞰的景色應該也不錯吧
How about buying a drone?
要不要買一台無人機呢
It could just fly to the summit in a snap.
咻地就能飛到山頂去了
If you buy something that expensive,
要是買那麼貴的東西
you'll bleed again.
妳又會流鼻血囉
"CURRENT LOCATION" But this campsite is so secluded.
(現在地) 但是這個露營場如此隱密
"TENT" How did you find it?
(帳篷) 妳是怎麼找到的啊?
While I was looking at geological sites in Izu,
我在看伊豆的地質景點時
I got interested in National Parks,
對國立公園有點感興趣
"MIZUGAKI CAMPSITE" so I browsed around on Guruguru Map.
(瑞牆露營場) 所以用咕嚕咕嚕地圖逛了一下
"CHICHIBU-TAMA-KAI NATIONAL PARK" I discovered this campsite by chance
(秩父多摩甲斐國立公園) 秩父多摩甲斐國立公園的周邊景點
while exploring the surroundings of Chichibu-Tama-Kai National Park.
結果就偶然發現了這個露營場
Since the weather is getting warmer,
反正天氣也越變越暖和了
we might try camping a bit further north from now on.
今後應該能試著 去北邊一點露營了吧
That sounds good.
確實 感覺不錯呢
It's almost 5 PM.
已經快五點了啊
Ms. Toba is so slow.
老師好慢喔
We can't even start dinner
因為鍋子和爐具都放在老師那裡
since she has the pots and pans.
也沒辦法先開始準備晚餐呢
Exactly.
就是說啊
If Ms. Toba says, "I can't make it after all,"
要是老師等一下說 "我果然還是來不了"
we're screwed.
我們就完蛋了呢
Then we'll have to munch on raw tomatoes.
那我們就只能啃生番茄了呢
Ms. Toba said she'll be here in ten minutes.
老師說她再10分鐘就到囉
We were just talking about her.
說人人到呢
Well then, let's start preparing.
那麼 開始來準備吧
First, let's wash and chop the ingredients.
總之先把食材洗一洗 切一切吧
The biggest culinary assault of the trip is about to begin.
這場旅行最大的美食攻擊要開始了
Gulp.
吞口水
Huh?
咦
UNDER REPAIR. DO NOT USE.
(修理中 禁止使用)
This campsite even has a pizza oven.
這個露營場還有披薩窯烤爐耶
You're right.
真的耶
But it's out of order.
不過現在好像不能用
Pizza…
披薩
If only I'd ordered it earlier!
早知道剛才就先吃了
What's up, Aki?
明 妳怎麼啦?
Well, actually back in Akeno…
沒有啦 其實在明野的時候…
"TOMATO CURRY" Aki-chan, what do you want to eat?
(番茄咖哩) 小明 妳想吃什麼?
The shop's recommendation
店家推薦的
"RECOMMENDED: CURRY FULL OF LOCAL VEGETABLES" was the curry filled with local vegetables.
(推薦 充滿當地蔬菜的咖哩) 好像是充滿當地蔬菜的咖哩
"PIZZA TOAST. TAKEAWAY" But I also wanted to try the pizza toast.
(披薩吐司 外帶) 但是我也有點想吃披薩吐司
But
不過
just pizza toast wouldn't be enough.
只吃披薩吐司的話 明顯會吃不飽
But getting both would be too much.
話雖如此 但兩個都點又太多了
"RECOMMENDED" So, I went with the recommended dish.
(本店推薦) 還是乖乖點店家推薦的餐點吧
So, I had curry.
所以我就點了咖哩
But I still wanted pizza.
果然還是想吃披薩呢
Pizza.
披薩
So now, seeing the pizza oven
所以 現在看到披薩窯烤爐
makes me really crave pizza!
才會超想吃披薩的
So you've been craving pizza since lunchtime.
原來妳從中午就想吃披薩了啊
Yes!
沒錯
"NAPOLI-STYLE PIZZA DOUGH" Look what this is!
(拿坡里風披薩餅皮) 妳看 這是什麼?
Is that… pizza dough?!
難道 是披薩餅皮?
That's right. We're making pizza today!
沒錯 我們今天還要烤披薩喔
Pizza!
烤披薩
Awesome, I'm so excited!
不妙 超開心的啦
But
可是
isn't the pizza oven out of order today?
今天不是不能用披薩窯烤爐嗎
Don't worry… we've got that covered.
別擔心…這部分就交給我們吧
Yup, yup.
沒錯…
Ms. Toba has arrived.
老師來了
Sorry for being late.
不好意思 拖到這個時候才來
No worries. You've had a long trip, Ms. Toba.
沒關係…老師工作辛苦了
Thank you for coming all this way.
您辛苦了
Your luggage is in the trunk.
妳們寄放的行李都在後車廂
Please help yourselves to it.
再麻煩妳們搬出來了
Got it.
好的
Now that we have the pots,
那麼 既然鍋子也到了
let's start cooking, Aoi-chan.
我們開始煮吧 小葵
Alrighty.
好啊
Ms. Toba,
老師
we bought some yakitori on our way here.
我們在來的路上有買烤雞肉串
If you don't mind, you can heat it up over the campfire
不介意的話 可以用篝火加熱
for a snack while we prepare dinner.
先吃一些果腹
Yakitori, you say?
烤雞肉串嗎
I just happened to bring some sake I bought in Izu.
我剛好帶了之前在伊豆買的日本酒
Yakitori and sake go perfectly together.
烤雞肉串跟日本酒非常搭呢
Thank you very much.
謝謝妳們
Five minutes later.
五分鐘後
This yakitori is amazing!
烤雞肉串超讚的
Even though I'm used to it,
雖然已經習以為常了
she really does turn into a different person entirely.
但真的瞬間就變成另一個人了呢
Goodbye, elegant Ms. Toba.
再見了 漂亮的鳥羽老師
Aki, what are you doing?
明 妳在幹嘛呀?
This is called cardboard smoking.
這叫做紙箱煙燻喔
I've seen that in camping magazines!
在野營雜誌上經常可以看到那個呢
That's right. I've wanted to try it for a while.
沒錯…我之前就很想試試了
What are you going to smoke?
妳要煙燻什麼東西呀?
First, the usual: cheese, nuts,
首先是常見的起司和堅果
and potato crisps.
還有洋芋片
But there's one more thing.
除此之外 還有另一個東西
"AKI-CHAN'S SPECIAL HOMEMADE SAUSAGE" Here it is, my treasured creation.
(小明特製自製香腸) 那就是我珍藏的這個
Ugh!
嘔
-Hey, did you just go "ugh"? -I need to go chop some wood.
-喂 妳們剛才是不是"嘔"了一聲? -我得去劈柴了
No…
沒有…
Don't worry.
放心吧
I followed the recipe and made it again.
後來我又按照食譜重新做了一次
-Tonight is going to be -Though I haven't
-今晚是死亡香腸攻擊啊 -雖然還沒試吃過就是了
No… I have to brace myself.
不…不行 我得打起精神來
Let's make some camp dishes with lots of tomatoes, Ena.
來用很多番茄做露營料理吧 惠那
All right.
好
"TOMATO JUICE 100% TOMATO" Let's start cooking.
(番茄汁 100%番茄) 開始料理
First, add tomato juice to the tomatoes
首先 在番茄裡加入番茄汁
and cook them in a pan until they break down.
並用平底鍋煮到爛為止
While the tomatoes are cooking,
在煮番茄的同時
pour olive oil into another pan with onions and garlic,
將橄欖油倒進裝有洋蔥 和蒜頭的另一個鍋子
and sauté until golden brown.
並拌炒到呈現黃褐色
Mana…
梅納…
Then, add pork belly to the pan
接著將豬五花肉倒進鍋子裡
and continue to sauté.
再繼續拌炒
What spell are you chanting over there?
妳從剛才開始就在唸什麼咒語啊
Once the pork is cooked,
等豬肉煮熟後
add bay leaves, red wine, and water.
加入月桂葉 紅酒 水
Let it simmer while skimming off the foam.
一邊熬煮 一邊撈出浮沫
My wine!
偶的酒
The tomatoes are ready.
番茄煮好囉
Add the cooked tomatoes, bouillon granules,
將煮爛的番茄和顆粒高湯粉
and salt to the pot,
以及鹽巴加入鍋子裡
and simmer until the volume is halved.
熬煮到份量只剩一半為止
Be careful not to burn it while simmering.
煮的時候要小心不要燒焦了
Next, remove the bay leaves.
接著將月桂葉拿出來
Add butter and simmer for a bit longer.
加入奶油 再稍微熬煮一下
Then, put cabbage and carrots into an empty frying pan and sauté.
然後將高麗菜和紅蘿蔔 放進空的平底鍋拌炒
Take out half once it's done.
炒好後先取出一半
Add yakisoba noodles and water, cover and steam,
再倒入炒麵和水悶燒
then add powdered sauce and stir.
並加入粉末醬汁攪拌一下
Finally, pour the tomato sauce from the pot over the noodles.
最後將鍋子裡的番茄醬汁淋在面上
Sprinkle with parsley and grated cheese.
灑上香芹和起司粉
And there you have it: Cheat Tomato Yakisoba,
故意用其他縣市的番茄
a dish using tomatoes from other prefectures, ironically created
來製作山梨縣中央市 為了推廣當地的番茄
to promote tomatoes from Chuo City, Yamanashi Prefecture.
而想出的番茄炒麵的悖德番茄炒麵
Complete!
就完成了
It looks delicious, but the name is a bit…
雖然看起來很好吃 但這名字實在是…
You don't often see yakisoba with tomato sauce.
很少看到炒麵會淋番茄醬汁呢
-Let's eat. -I'm digging in.
-我要開動了 -偶要開動了
Yum!
好吃
Delicious.
好好吃
It's really good!
真的很好吃呢
The tomato aroma is completely locked in.
番茄的香氣全都鎖在裡面了
This is awesome!
不妙啊
This might be one of the best camping dishes I've ever had.
這搞不好是我吃過的露營料理中 數一數二好吃的
By the way,
話說回來
why did Nadeshiko start narrating halfway through?
為什麼從中途開始 就變成撫子在解說了啊
"NADESHIKO'S DAD" Because my family
(撫子爸爸) 因為這道料理
"CHEAT TOMATO YAKISOBA" put this recipe on "cook recipe".
(悖德番茄炒麵) 有投稿在我家的cook recipe上呀
So Nadeshiko's dad came up with the name?
原來那名字是撫子爸爸取的嗎
Everyone in Nadeshiko's family writes recipes on the site.
撫子她家所有人都有在寫cook recipe喔
That's right.
沒錯
As expected from the Kagamihara family.
不愧是各務原家
My dad writes some pretty weird recipes.
我爸爸都寫一些有點奇怪的料理
Mum writes about everyday home cooking.
媽媽是寫每天的家常料理
I write about dishes I've made while camping.
我則是寫露營時做過的料理
"MITARASHI DANGO ICE," Sakura writes about lazy recipes
(醬油糰子冰) 姊姊是寫五分鐘
"PUT MITARASHI DANGO ON ICE"
(把醬油糰子放到冰上)
you can make in five minutes.
就能完成的懶人點心喔
Even Sakura's articles are lazy.
姊姊連文章內容都很偷懶呢
But they're really simple and tasty.
但真的既簡單又美味喔
That was really good.
超好吃的
Makes you want to try making it at home.
這道料理會讓人 想在家自己做做看呢
Thanks for the compliments, everyone.
謝謝大家的稱讚
Alright, next up…
那麼 接著來烤…
Aki-chan's long-awaited pizza!
小明期待已久的披薩吧
Time for pizza!
輪到披薩啦
Finally, I can satisfy my pizza craving!
終於可以滿足我對披薩的慾望了
That's great, Aki-chan.
太好了呢 小明
First, lightly fry the pizza dough with a bit of olive oil.
先用少量的橄欖油煎烤披薩餅皮
So exciting!
好興奮
Then add cheese, cabbage, bean sprouts, tempura bits,
再放上起司 高麗菜 豆芽菜 天婦羅花
and pork belly.
以及豬五花肉
Next, pour in some flour mixed with hot water.
接著淋上用熱水糊化的麵粉
So exciting…?
好興奮…?
In another pan, stir-fry some noodles and fry up an egg.
再用另一個平底鍋炒麵和煎蛋
Once the flour mixture sets,
等麵粉凝固後
place the pizza dough on the stir-fry
將餅皮放在炒麵上
and press with a spatula.
並用鍋鏟按壓
Then put the dough and noodles on the egg
接著將餅皮連同炒麵放在蛋上
and press again with the spatula.
再用鍋鏟按壓
When the egg is cooked, flip everything over.
等蛋煎好後翻面
Sprinkle with pickled ginger and seaweed,
撒上紅薑絲和海苔
then drizzle with sauce and mayonnaise.
最後再淋上醬汁和美乃滋就完成了
It turned into okonomiyaki!
變成大阪燒了啦
If you put sake in the freezer,
一旦把日本酒放進冷凍庫
it becomes cold but doesn't freeze.
酒會變得冰涼 但又不至於結冰
This phenomenon is called "supercooling."
這種現象叫做"過冷"
In this state, pouring the sake into a glass causes slight agitation,
如果在這種狀態下 將酒倒入杯中
leading the molecules to form
會因為些微的碰撞 導致分子逐漸結合
a slush-like consistency,
就能做出雪酪狀的酒
known as "sake granita."
也就是所謂的"霙酒"
It's nice to enjoy sake this way occasionally,
偶爾用這種方式喝日本酒
isn't it?
也挺不錯的吧?
Why does Ms. Toba look strange?
老師怎麼看起來怪怪的?
That's just how she usually looks.
畢竟她平時都是那副模樣
I wanted to see elegant Ms. Toba
所以我才想在回憶裡
drinking in my memories.
看看老師高雅喝酒的樣子
But it feels a bit unsettling.
但這樣反而讓人有點不舒服耶
Let's go back to normal then.
那就恢復原狀吧
The sake is delicious!
酒超好喝的
Good.
很好
Trying the okonomiyaki made with pizza dough.
試吃用披薩餅皮做的大阪燒
This is pretty good,
其實這樣也滿好吃的
but I want pizza!
但是 我想吃的是披薩啊
Settle down.
放心吧
"NAPOLI-STYLE PIZZA DOUGH" This pizza dough comes in a pack of three.
(拿坡里風披薩餅皮) 這個披薩餅皮是三片裝的
Really?
真的嗎
Next, let's use the dough as naan to wrap minced meat curry and sausages.
接著把餅皮當作饢餅 包肉末咖哩和香腸吃吧
Good idea.
好主意
Hey, stop that!
喂 住手啊
How to make pizza in a frying pan.
用平底鍋烤披薩的方法
First, cover the frying pan with a lid
首先 將平底鍋的蓋子蓋上
and heat it on high.
以大火熱鍋
Then, spread tomato sauce over the pizza dough
接著將披薩餅皮塗滿番茄醬汁
and top with bacon, asparagus, and capsicum.
並撒上培根 蘆筍 甜椒
Add tomatoes and basil,
再放上番茄和羅勒
and drizzle with mayonnaise.
淋上美乃滋
Finally, sprinkle with pizza cheese.
最後撒上披薩用的起司
The frying pan will now act like a pizza oven.
此時平底鍋裡 已經變成窯烤爐狀態
To keep the heat inside,
為了不要讓裡面的熱氣消散
open the lid slightly, pour in a little olive oil,
將鍋蓋打開一個小縫 倒入些微的橄欖油
and quickly slide the pizza into the pan.
再迅速地將披薩滑入鍋內
Then, cook on low heat until the cheese melts.
接著以小火慢慢煎烤到 披薩上的起司融化為止
So you can create a pizza oven effect
原來只要這麼做
with a frying pan by doing this.
平底鍋也能達到 類似窯烤爐的狀態啊
Once the pizza is cooked,
等披薩烤好後
use a blowtorch to slightly char the surface
再用噴槍將表面烤到微焦
and add a dash of black pepper.
並撒上少許的黑胡椒
The slow-cooked tomato sauce pizza is ready.
細火慢熬的番茄醬汁披薩就完成了
It's pizza!
是披薩啊
Rich tomato sauce with a buttery aroma, topped with fresh tomatoes,
帶有奶油香氣的濃郁番茄醬汁 配上滿滿的生番茄
mayonnaise, and cheese…
再加上美乃滋和起司
This is it!
就是這個
This is exactly what I wanted to eat!
我想吃的就是這個啊
Is it so good that you're crying?
居然好吃到哭了?
Well, we did keep teasing her and making her wait anxiously.
畢竟我們還一直逗弄她 害她等得很焦急嘛
Why is Nadeshiko crying too?
為什麼連撫子也哭了?
Pizza-flavoured crisps are tasty,
雖然披薩洋芋片很好吃
but they're not pizza.
但不管怎麼吃 都沒有吃披薩的感覺
Well, that can't be helped.
這…這也是沒辦法的嘛
The pizza is perfectly cooked.
連披薩裡面都有烤熟
It's really well done.
真的烤得很好呢
Thanks to the blowtorch.
多虧有噴槍
The cheese aroma is fully released.
起司的香氣都被激發出來了
Oh, right. Almost forgot about my smoking project.
對了…差點忘記我還在煙燻了
Cardboard smoking.
紙箱煙燻
After smoking for an hour,
在經過一小時的煙燻後
let it sit in the box for another hour
為了讓味道充分滲透
to let the flavours develop.
又在紙箱中靜置了一小時
It looks good.
感覺不錯…
I didn't expect homemade smoking to give such a nice colour.
原來自製的也能呈現出 這麼像煙燻的顏色啊
The smoked nuts have a great texture!
確實有煙燻堅果的口感呢
The smoked potato crisps are tasty too!
煙燻洋芋片也很美味耶
Right?
對吧
The cheese has turned into a perfect smoked cheese colour and looks really good!
起司也完全是煙燻起司的顏色 看起來真好吃
Smoked food goes well with beer.
煙燻食物和啤酒很搭喔
Ms. Toba seems to like it too.
老師好像也很喜歡呢
Now for what you've all been waiting for…
接著是各位期盼已久的…
Aki-chan's special homemade sausage, smoked version!
小明特製自製香腸 煙燻版
It's… it's the deadly sausage attack…!
是…是死亡香腸攻擊
I… I forgot about this.
都…都忘記還有這個了
A… Aki, we can skip this one.
明…明 我們就先不用了
Don't be shy, I made enough for everyone.
別客氣 我有準備所有人的份
Come on, eat it while it's hot.
來 趁熱吃吧
Ena!
惠那
Aoi-chan, this sausage is really good!
小葵 這個很好吃喔
Oh, you're right.
真的耶
It might not compare to store-bought sausages,
雖然沒辦法和市售的香腸比
but it's 100 times better than the ones we made during our yard camping.
但已經比之前在庭院露營時 好吃幾百倍了
Hooray!
好耶
That's great, Aki-chan.
太好了呢 小明
Now for the final dish.
最後一道料理
Add water to the remaining tomato sauce,
將水倒進剩下的番茄醬汁裡
then add the sautéed cabbage and carrots,
再放入炒過的高麗菜和紅蘿蔔
boiled soybeans, and chopped tomatoes
以及水煮大豆和切塊的番茄
to make minestrone.
燉煮成義式蔬菜湯
Ending the chilly night at Mizugaki
在瑞牆的寒夜裡
with a bowl of minestrone really warms the body and soul.
最後來上一碗義式蔬菜湯 讓身心都暖和起來了
Though, it feels more like pork and bean stew
雖然與其說是義式蔬菜湯
than minestrone.
感覺更像豬肉燉大豆
Actually, the tomato yakisoba sauce should have been made with minced meat.
其實番茄炒麵的醬汁 應該要用絞肉做
But I thought the minestrone
但義式蔬菜湯和五花肉比較搭
would go better with pork belly, so I made a little tweak.
所以我就稍微改良了一下
You're so particular about the details.
連細節都好講究喔
It's amazing how we made three dishes
居然能用番茄醬汁做出三道料理
with the tomato sauce.
真厲害啊
However,
不過
even though we used so many tomatoes,
我們明明用了那麼多番茄
we still have two whole bags left.
居然還剩下整整兩袋啊
We shouldn't have each packed a bag.
早知道就不要一人裝一袋了
Seriously.
真是的
It's all because Aki-chan said it'd be more fun if we all did it.
都怪小明說什麼 大家一起裝比較有趣啦
Goodness.
真是的
Hey, it was your idea!
是妳們說的好嗎
By the way,
話說回來
I haven't seen Chikuwa for a while.
好像從剛才開始就沒看到竹輪耶
Where'd Chikuwa go?
牠跑去哪裡了?
Huh?
咦
You're right. Chikuwa?
真的耶 竹輪?
Chikuwa!
竹輪
Chikuwa ran into that little window!
居然跑進小視窗裡面了
It's so warm inside here!
小視窗裡面超級溫暖的耶
It's just a memory,
明明是回憶
but why are we outside here in the cold
我們卻乖乖待在外面吹冷風
like idiots?
簡直像笨蛋一樣啊
Wait, Aki!
等等 明
That's cheating!
自己跑進去太狡猾了啦
I want to go in too!
我也要進去
Then I want to go in too.
那我也要進去
Hey, don't push me!
喂 別推我啊
I want to go in too!
偶也要進去
And so,
於是
everyone except Hanpen ran inside.
除了半片以外的人 都跑進去了
My, my.
真是的
Can't we just have a nice, peaceful night by the campfire?
難得的露營之夜 就不能安靜地度過嗎
The campfire feels so warm.
篝火真暖和
But this is a splendid campsite.
不過 這個露營場真的很棒呢
Although it's not the most convenient
雖然交通不算方便
in terms of transportation,
但就是這樣
that's what makes camping so leisurely.
才能悠悠哉哉地露營啊
So,
那麼
let's end the memories of Mizugaki here.
瑞牆的露營回憶就到此為止
Since everyone has run off,
因為大家都跑走了
I'll wrap it up.
就由我來結尾吧
"SUBSCRIBE" Don't forget to like
(訂閱頻道) 請大家別忘了按讚
"HANPEN'S GOOD DAYS" and subscribe to the channel.
(半片好日子) 以及訂閱頻道喔
That's about it.
大概就是這樣
We enjoyed a spring-like winter camping trip at Mizugaki.
我們在瑞牆享受了一場 春天的冬季露營
So, you guys went on a camping trip like that
原來我們去大井川的時候
when we went to Oigawa.
妳們去了一趟這樣的露營啊
Although, a lot of it was made up.
雖然很多都是假的啦
Well, that's the end of the camping stories.
那麼 露營的故事也說完了
Let's call it a day for today's chopping.
今天的木柴就劈到這裡吧
Yeah.
是啊
There's still a lot of firewood left.
還有好多木柴喔
While chopping wood, I thought of something.
在劈柴的時候 我想到了一件事
If we gather firewood like this every year,
如果我們每年都像這樣領木柴
chop and dry it, and then our juniors
劈木柴 晾乾木柴
can use them to make fires when they go camping,
然後學弟妹們去露營時 就用這些木柴生火
it feels like we're passing on a tradition,
像這樣不斷傳承下去
like we're a real club.
總覺得很有社團的感覺呢
Sure does.
是啊
It'd be great if we get juniors to join our club.
要是能有學弟妹加入就好了
I'll make sure we get those juniors!
我一定會抓學弟妹進來給妳看的
We'll become a real club this year!
今年絕對要晉升成社團
"WE CAN GO FLOWER VIEWING AT THIS CAMPSITE" Rin-chan messaged me saying she found
(這個露營場好像能賞櫻喔) 小凜傳訊息跟我說
a campsite where we can enjoy cherry blossoms.
找到一個可以賞櫻的露營場囉
I didn't know there was a campsite in that place.
沒想到這種地方也有露營場呢
Yeah.
對啊
Isn't this near Nadeshiko's place?
這裡是不是在撫子家附近呀?
Really?
真的耶
It sounds great! Let's go with that!
不錯耶 就選這裡吧
All of us can finally go camping together again since Izu.
繼伊豆露營之後 大家又能一起去露營了呢
Time to come up with the menu.
得想想要煮什麼了
Alright, let's plan our cherry blossom viewing camping trip!
好 來制定賞櫻露營的計畫吧
OUTDOOR ACTIVITIES CLUB
(野外活動同好會)
GRADUATION CEREMONY SPRING BREAK BEGINS!
(結業式 開始放春假囉)
Rin-chan!
小凜
The eagerly awaited
從明天開始
and heart-pounding spring break starts tomorrow!
就是令人雀躍不已且期待已久 心臟怦怦跳的春假了呢
I wouldn't say heart-pounding…
心臟怦怦跳是多餘的吧
Do you have any plans
賞櫻露營前
before our cherry blossom viewing trip?
小凜有打算去哪裡玩嗎
Hmm…
這個嘛
I haven't decided yet.
我還沒想好要去哪裡
Oh, cherry blossom pictures.
是櫻花的照片
I took some too.
我也有拍喔
Look!
妳看
Let me see the ones you took, Rin-chan.
也讓我看看小凜拍的吧
They're probably all similar.
應該都長得差不多吧
NEXT EPISODE: BIKE TRIP AND CHERRY BLOSSOM VIEWING TRIP
(下集 機車旅行和賞櫻巡禮)
WHEN ENJOYING CAMPING, BE SURE TO FOLLOW THE RULES
(享受露營時…) (務必遵守露營場和其設施的規定)
DON'T FORGET TO PUT OUT YOUR CAMPFIRE AND DISPOSE OF YOUR GARBAGE.
(別忘了滅火和帶走垃圾)
TEMPERATURES CAN CHANGE QUICKLY, SO CHECK THE WEATHER FORECAST BEFOREHAND.
(由於氣溫可能會急速變化) (記得事先確認天氣預報)
WEAR WARM CLOTHING IF NECESSARY TO PREVENT COLD.
(必要時穿著保暖衣物防寒)